fa.com 2019-04-22

# Privacy

## Privacy Statement

**1\. General**

Henkel AG & Co. KGaA, hereinafter referred to as Henkel, respects the privacy of each person who visits our website. Now we would like to inform you of the type of data collected by Henkel and how they are used. You will also learn how you can exercise your data subjects’ rights.

Any changes to this Data Protection Statement will be published on this page. This enables you to inform yourself at any time about which data we are collecting and how we use such data.

This Data Protection Statement does not apply to websites accessible via hyperlinks on Henkel websites.

**2\. Collection, use and processing of personal data**

Name of the responsible entity: Henkel AG & Co. KGaA

Address of the responsible entity: Henkelstrasse 67, 40589 Duesseldorf, Germany

Henkel uses personal data primarily to provide this website to the users. Any further processing of the data only occurs on the basis of other statutory duties or permissions or if the respective user has consented towards Henkel. Henkel stores and processes data specifically for the following purposes:  
When users visit the website, Henkel automatically collects and stores certain data.  This includes: the IP address or device ID allocated to the respective end-device which we need for transmitting requested content (e.g. especially content, texts, images, and product information as well as data files provided for downloading, etc.), the activity of users in the context of the website, the type of respective end-device, the used type of browser as well as the date and time of use.  
Henkel stores this information for a maximum of 7 days for the purpose of recognizing and pursuing misuse.  
Henkel uses this information also for improvements to the service’s presentation, features and functionalities as well as general administration tasks.  
Aside from this, Henkel deletes or anonymizes the data on use, including the IP addresses, without undue delay as soon as they are no longer needed for the above mentioned purposes.  
The processing and use of the data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that (1) the processing is necessary for the provision of the website; or (2) Henkel has an overriding legitimate interest in ensuring and enhancing the functionality and error-free operation of the website and that it is tailored to the users’ needs.

**3.     Further Personal Data processing**

a)    Consumer request table  
You may have provided your contact data via our contact form. We will use your data for the purpose of replying to your request.

The processing and use of your data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that the processing is necessary for processing your request.

If you have not given consent to a longer storage duration e.g. in the course of our customer relationship management we will store the data no longer than needed in order to fulfill the aforementioned purpose or as long as required in case any statutory retention obligation applies.

b)    Raffles  
You may have provided your contact data and your address while participating in a raffle which we offer from time to time on our website. We will use your data for the purpose of conducting the raffle.

We will not forward your data to any third party unless for the distribution of prizes or for conducting the raffle.

The processing and use of your data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that the processing is necessary for conducting the raffle.

If you have not given consent to a longer storage duration e.g. in the course of our customer relationship management we will store the data no longer than needed in order to fulfill the aforementioned purpose or as long as required in case any statutory retention obligation applies.

c)    Product test  
You may have provided your contact data and your address while participating in product tests. We will use your data for the purpose of conducting the product test.

We will not forward your data to any third party unless for the purpose of conducting the product test.  
The processing and use of your data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that the processing is necessary for carrying out the product test.

If you have not given consent to a longer storage duration e.g. in the course of our customer relationship management we will store the data no longer than needed in order to fulfill the aforementioned purpose or as long as required in case any statutory retention obligation applies.

d)    Webinar  
You may have provided your contact data, e.g your email address while participating in webinars. We will use your data for the purpose of providing the webinar.

We will not forward your data to any third party unless for the purpose of conducting the webinar.  
The processing and use of your data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that the processing is necessary for providing the webinar to you.

If you have not given consent to a longer storage duration e.g. in the course of our customer relationship management we will store the data no longer than needed in order to fulfill the aforementioned purpose or as long as required in case any statutory retention obligation applies.

e)    Surveys  
You may have provided your contact data, e.g your email address while participating in a survey. We will use your data for the purpose of conducting the survey.

We will not forward your data to any third party unless for the purpose of conducting the survey.  
The processing and use of your data is based on statutory provisions which justify those operations on the grounds that the processing is necessary for conducting the survey.

If you have not given consent to a longer storage duration e.g. in the course of our customer relationship management we will store the data no longer than needed in order to fulfill the aforementioned purpose or as long as required in case any statutory retention obligation applies.

**4.        Consent / Withdrawal of Consent**

a)    Consumer/ Customer Relationship Management/ Onlince Commuities

You may have given consent  that Henkel processes

•    your contact data which you may have provided to Henkel,  
•    the content and circumstances of your electronic communication with Henkel such as contact forms or e-mail,  
•    your usage of Henkel websites,  
•    data on your participation in Henkel’s online trainings,  
•    activities on Henkel’s Social Media sites (in Blogs, Facebook Fanpages etc.)  
•    …

 in the framework of Henkel’s customer/ consumer relationship management/ online community  

for the purposes of

•    advertising (by post, in browser, in app and as specified below if you provide an additional consent),  
•    rendering technical advice such as usage of products or technologies,  
•    market research, and  
•    providing online services such as eLearning, webinars  
•    communication in relation to events  
•    conducting surveys  
•    …

To achieve the selected purposes Henkel may  
-    combine the above listed data with other data Henkel may have legally collected about you for instance from raffles or other website activities, and  
-    analyze the data in order to determine relevant advertising measures.

In the course of this analysis Henkel applies an automated methodology that helps prioritize leads for sales. Contacts are categorized according to their online and off-line activities. Based on the category they are assigned to and the location they are the contacts are assigned to sales persons and receive different information on our products and services as well as advertising material.  

You may have given consent that Henkel may forward your personal data to the GFK for the following purpose:  
-    matching and updating the contact addresses. 

We will store the data only as long as the consent is valid or as long as required in case of any statutory retention obligations.

You may withdraw your consent with effect for the future at any time, for example by clicking the respective hyperlink provided either in the confirmation e-mail or by clicking [HERE].  The withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

b)    Electronic Mail Advertising

You may further have declared your consent  that Henkel may contact you regarding offers, products and services regarding products from Henkel’s Adhesive Technologies range via electronic mail (e-mail, sms, mms, instant message) and/or telephone.

We will use your data as set forth above under section 4a. of this Data Protection Statement to provide you with respective advertising measures.   

You may withdraw your consent with effect for the future at any time, for example by clicking the respective hyperlink provided either in the confirmation e-mail or by clicking [HERE].  The withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

**5.     Cookies, Pixel, Fingerprints**  
This website uses cookies and similar technologies. Technically necessary cookies will be used automatically. Other cookies (or similar technologies) will only be applied based on your prior consent. You can find more information on the Cookies used by our website and their purposes in our Cookie Policy. There, you will also find information on how to withdraw your consent for the future.  
Your preference is set for the named domain, per browser and computer. Therefore, if you visit our website at home and work or with different browsers, you need to refuse data storage with every device or browser.  
**

6.    Web Tracking

**  
a)    Google Analytics

Provided you have consented, this website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). For this purpose, a cookie is installed on your computer. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. 

We have activated the IP anonymization, this means Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA.  

On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. 

Objection to data collection:  
You can also prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by changing your browser settings or by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en

b)    Google DoubleClick  
Provided you have consented, we use the Google DoubleClick function on our website in order to evaluate the use of the website and make it possible for us, Google and other advertisers who co-operate with DoubleClick to be able to provide you with user-relevant advertising. For this purpose, a cookie is installed on your computer. This cookie collects information on the advertising shown in your browser and which advertisements you click. The information generated by the cookie on your use of website will be transferred to a Google server in the US and stored there. Based on the information collected, interest-related advertisements are being displayed in your browser.

Objection to data collection:  
You can also permanently deactivate the DoubleClick cookie by changing your browser settings or with the aid of a browser plug-in. With the plug-in, your deactivation settings for this browser are retained, even if you delete all cookies. You can obtain the browser plug-in for permanent deactivation https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.

c)    Facebook Custom Audience Pixel  
We participate in Facebook's Custom Audience program which - provided you have consented - enables us to display personalized ads to you when you also have subscribed to Facebook and log in into your Facebook account. This tool allows us to personalize our ads based on your usage of our website in order to provide ads specifically tailored for you. To this end we share your email address or phone number in a hashed format which permits Facebook to identify you in case you have also subscribed to Facebook.

Objection to data collection:  
You can adjust your ad preferences by changing your browser settings or through your Facebook settings if you do not want to receive interest-based ads on Facebook.

**7.     Commerce Connector**  
On our website we are using the Buy Now Button. The Buy-Now-Button is provided and controlled by Commerce Connector. Detailed information on the functionality and data processing can be found under the following link:

**8.     Your Data Subject Rights / Data Protection Officer**  
At any time, you may assert the right to access your data. Additionally, provided that the respective requirements are met, you may assert the following rights:  
•    Right to rectification  
•    Right to erasure  
•    Right to restriction of processing  
•    Right to lodge a complaint with the respectively competent data protection supervisory authority  
•    Right to data portability (as of May 25th 2018)

Right to object  
In case of processing activities involving your personal data that are carried out on basis of a legitimate interest of Henkel, you have the right to object against such processing of your personal data at any time for reasons resulting from your specific situation. Henkel will stop that processing unless Henkel can prove important reasons for the processing which deserve protection which outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend against legal claims.

In these cases, or if you have any other questions or wishes in connection with regard to your personal data, please send an e-mail or a letter to our data protection officer, Mr. Frank Liebich, Henkel AG & Co. KGaA, Henkelstrasse 67, D 40191 Düsseldorf, Germany (E-Mail: Datenschutz@henkel.com).

**9.     Use of Social Media Plug-ins**  
Plug-ins (“plug-ins”) of different social media networks are embedded in our web pages. The associated services are provided by the respective companies (“providers”). These providers are:  
Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). For an overview of the Facebook plug-ins and their appearance, go to: https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins  
Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”). For an overview of the Twitter buttons and their appearance, go to: https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons  
Google+ and YouTube are provided by     Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA (“Google”). For an overview of the Google+ plug-ins and their appearance, go to: https://developers.google.com/+/web/; for the YouTube plugins, go to: https://developers.google.com/youtube/subscribe/  
Instagram is provided by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA („Instagram“). For an overview of the Instagram plug-ins and their appearance, go to: http://blog.instagram.com/post/36222022872/introducing-instagram-badges  
LinkedIn is provided by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“LinkedIn”). For an overview of the LinkedIn plug-ins and their appearance, go to: https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins#  
To increase the protection afforded to your data when you visit our web pages, these plug-ins are implemented as “2-click buttons.” This form of integration ensures that, when accessing a page from within our website containing such plug-ins, you are not automatically connected to the providers’ servers. Only if you activate the plug-ins and thereby permit for data transmission, the browser will create a direct link to the providers’ servers. The content of the various plug-ins is then transmitted by the provider concerned directly to your browser and then displayed on your screen.  
The plug-in tells the provider which of our website pages you have accessed. If, while viewing our website, you are logged into your user account with the respective provider, he is able to collate your interest, i.e. the information you are accessing, with your user account. On making use of any of the plug-in functions (e.g. clicking the “Like” button, leaving a comment), this information too will be transmitted by the browser directly to the provider for retention.  
Further information on the collection and use of data by the providers and on the rights and possibilities available to you for protecting your privacy in these circumstances can be found in the providers’ data protection/privacy policies:  
Data protection/privacy policy issued by Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/policy.php  
Data protection/privacy policy issued by Twitter: https://twitter.com/Data Protection  
Data protection/privacy policy issued by Google: https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/Data Protection/  
Data protection/privacy policy issued by Instagram: https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388/
